Gabriel Emilio López Ojeda

Professional profile

I am a software engineer with three years of experience in both web and mobile development. My expertise includes working with React and Node.js technologies, such as Next.js, as well as developing mobile applications using React Native and native code for library development when needed. I am a curious individual who is always eager to learn and grow. I highly value collaboration and teamwork, which I believe are essential qualities in the roles I am applying for.

Experience

HPMLED April 2024 - May 2024

Freelance Remote

• Developed new website on Shopify utilizing React/Remix/Hydrogen, effectively enhancing the company's online visibility by replacing an outdated and neglected site.

INTELA Servicios Corporativos

October 2021 - March 2024

Software Engineer Remote

- Led the development of a React Native mobile app, deployed on App Store and Play Store. The app simplified employee tasks, resulting in quicker leave requests, better attendance tracking, and easier access to company news.
- Contributed to the development of an administrative panel using Next.js. This panel managed roles, permissions, and data displayed in the mobile app.
- Contributed to the development of two internal mobile apps for the HR department using React Native.
- Utilized a content management system (CMS) within the administrative panel, primarily to facilitate easy management of resources such as images, videos, and articles authored by non-developers.
- Created multiple scripts in JS or Python to massively handle and load data to databases from JSON or XLSX files.
- Created multiple cloud functions using Firebase and TypeScript.
- Managed deployment of mobile apps in App Store Connect, and Google Play Console.
- Managed deployment of cloud functions using Firebase.
- Fixed and debugged errors in code and deployments.

Baja Ferries (assigned through the consulting firm Bikey)

May 2021 - October 2021

Software engineer intern

Monterrey, N.L

• Contributed to the development of a travel expenses website using SAP Gateway with an ODATA API for the backend and SAPUI5 for the frontend, deployed on-premise to the SAP Fiori launchpad.

PIASA (assigned through the consulting firm Dobresoft)

October 2020 - March 2021

Software engineer intern

Monterrey, N.L

• Contributed in the development of a website to track expenses against departmental budgets. Extracted data from SAP ECC to an SQL database. The backend was built with Node.js and Express, and the frontend with SAPUI5. Implemented custom access control due to non-HANA instance constraints.

Education

Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León

August 2017 - August 2022

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Monterrey, N.L.

• Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Foundations, Computer Architecture, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Architecture

Technical Skills

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Java, Go, Lua, Bash, SQL, HTML, CSS

Technologies: React.js, React Native, Next.js, Remix, Shopify Hydrogen, Express.js, Node.js, Electron, Tailwind, GraphQL

Databases: MongoDB, Postgres, MS-SQL

Tools: Git, Postman, Figma

DevOps: Docker, GCP Cloud, AWS Lambda, Firebase Functions, Firebase Hosting, Vercel, Linux (configuring and

managing)

Others: Data Modeling, Agile, Scrum, SOLID, Design Patterns, Debugging, Root Cause Analysis, Web Development,

Front-End, Back-End